# JULIET DI FRENZA

MEDIA RELATIONS SPECIALIST

#### SKILLS

Drafting Pitches/Press Releases
Media Relations/Outreach
Cultural Awareness
Client Relations
Networking
Storytelling
Negotiation
Fundraising
Public Speaking
Team Development
Delegation and Empowerment

#### PROGRAMS

Cision Gorkana MailChimp Word Suite PR Newswire

#### QUALITIES

Enthusiasm
Persuasion
Integrity
Honesty
Empathy
Flexibility
Creativity
Leadership
Persistence

jdifrenza@gmail.com



917-620-3744



#### ABOUT ME / HIGHLIGHTS

Enthusiastic specialist offering media relations through traditional print and digital media outlets, and social media channels. Additional experience with fundraising and development complement communications offerings.

- Generated a strategy for the international law firm, Morrison Foerster's Financial Services Practice, resulting in coverage that was selected as one of the most successful strategies for the U.S. office in Q2.
- Arranged, prepared, and attended the first Private Equity International podcast connecting the outlet with lawyers in multiple cities.
- Assisted with the PR for former Fox News anchor Gretchen Carlson in the lawsuit against former Fox CEO Roger Ailes, which required tact and sensitivity.
- Built, trained and directed a nonprofit canvass office that went on to break five years of fundraising records.

#### EXPERIENCE

MEDIA RELATIONS SPECIALIST | FROM APRIL 2018 - PRESENT

- Working to fulfill media relations needs for PR agencies and small companies. Amongst offerings: media relations strategy, pitch writing/press releases, public relations support, outreach and more.
- Also, fundraising part-time for a nonprofit's capital campaign.

LAK PUBLIC RELATIONS | FROM DEC 2017 - MAR 2018 Account Manager

- Managed media relations for international law firms in a midtown agency.
- Drafted press releases and pitch notes; compiled Cision media lists; researched and generated story ideas; placed client commentaries; scheduled and prepared lawyers for podcast interviews; pulled together daily press coverage reports.
- Cultivated new press relationships while maintaining existing connections.
- Worked closely with outlets including Dow Jones Newswire, The Wall Street Journal, Law360, Forbes, Private Equity International, Legaltech News, and Kiplinger's.

FIREBRAND GROUP | FROM MAY 2017 - OCT 2017 Media Relations Specialist (Independent Contractor)

- Conducted press outreach for digital marketing conference, welcomed press at the event and secured coverage in Forbes and industry website, Augmented Reality Daily. Assisted with day-of tasks during the event including moments of crisis.
- Handled PR for a Chinese company's augmented reality app launch; worked with an international clientele in a timely manner.

# JULIET DI FRENZA

MEDIA RELATIONS SPECIALIST

### EDUCATION

Stony Brook University

B.A. in Cultural Anthropology

B.A. in Women's Studies

### CAUSES

- Environment
- Social Justice

#### EXPERIENCE

RIPP MEDIA/PUBLIC RELATIONS | FROM APRIL 2015 - MAY 2017 Account Manager

- Managed media relations for international law firms and BigPharma at a boutique PR agency in midtown.
- Handled multiple accounts simultaneously; compiled media lists; generated pitches following the news cycle. Assisted with crisis management.
- Proactively arranged an opportunity for an attorney, securing coverage that was featured on the front page of the Wall Street Journal's Risk & Compliance Report.
- Developed and maintained industry press relationships; arranged interviews that led to coverage in Reuters, Forbes, The Washington Post, Law360, Politico, CNN, and others.
- Drafted media briefs, meeting agendas, and monthly activity reports.

TOURNEAU | FROM FEB 2012 - MAR 2015 Luxury Sales Professional

- High-end watch sales to a domestic and international clientele in a fast-paced national watch store, with price points up to \$40K; met store goals and led product workshops.
- Maintained client relationships and provided customer service that was highlighted in a positive Yelp review.

LINCOLN CENTER FOR THE PERFORMING ARTS  $\mid$  FROM MAR 2011 - JAN 2012 Sales Agent

• Handled subscription sales for an established New York arts institution.

CARNEGIE HALL | FROM MAR 2010 - MAR 2011 Fundraiser

• Fundraised for music education programs and assisted with training.

NEW YORK PUBLIC INTEREST RESEARCH GROUP | FROM MAY 2003 - AUG 2006 Fundraising Director & Campus Organizer

- Built and directed an environmental campaign office that broke the fundraising records of the previous five years; fundraised; handled large-scale job inquiries; trained and mentored canvassers; drafted material for daily staff briefings.
- Organized local press conferences and events securing the attendance of community legislators and local media; facilitated student advocacy and activism; organized lobby trips to Albany; built coalitions with campus organizations.
- Began as a fundraiser in the five boroughs for this New York state consumer and environmental advocacy nonprofit and actively fundraised throughout tenure.

jdifrenza@gmail.com



917-620-3744

